mcstate.com 2011-06-15

# Privacy Policy :: McDonalds.com

Thank you for visiting us online at McDonalds.com. At McDonald's, we strive to do everything we can to respect the trust customers have in our brand and our commitment to your privacy is no exception. We are committed to protecting and safeguarding consumer privacy on the Internet, especially for children.

Thanks again for visiting our website and for placing your trust in McDonald's.

## McDonald's Internet Privacy Policy

McDonald's Corporation ("McDonald's") is pleased to provide information to all of its customers about its online privacy policy. Please be assured that McDonald's uses its best efforts to protect the privacy of visitors to this web site.

## Types of Information We Collect and How It Is Used

McDonald's only gathers personal information, such as, first and last names, addresses and email addresses, when voluntarily submitted by you. For example, personal information may be collected from you in order to get your feedback on our web sites and our products or to enter you in one of our contests or sweepstakes.

## Sharing of Personal Information

McDonald's may share personal information within the McDonald's Family. The McDonald's Family includes McDonald's Corporation, our franchisees, our subsidiaries and our affiliates. Of course, any use of this information by the McDonald's Family will comply with this policy. Occasionally, with your permission, we will send marketing information to you, such as discount coupons, information about new product offerings, etc. If you do not elect to receive such materials, we will not send them to you.

Companies may be engaged by McDonald's to perform a variety of functions, such as, fulfilling orders, assisting with promotions, providing technical services for our web sites, etc. These companies may have access to personal information if needed to perform such functions. However, these companies may only use such personal information for the purpose of performing that function and may not use it for any other purpose.

McDonald's does not sell, transfer or disclose personal information to third parties outside the McDonald's Family. However, with your permission, we will, on occasion send marketing information on behalf of one of our business partners about products or services they provide that may be of interest to you. You may be asked if you wish to receive marketing materials from McDonald's business partners. If you elect to receive such materials, McDonald's will not share your personal information with such partners but rather will send a mailing or email on behalf of the partners.

McDonald's reserves the right to use or disclose any information as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request, to protect the integrity of the site, to fulfill your requests, or to cooperate in any law enforcement investigation or an investigation on a matter of public safety.

## Our Privacy Policy Regarding Children

McDonald's is very sensitive to privacy issues. We are proud of our longtime commitment to our customers. We are especially careful in any communications with one of our most treasured customers - children.

On our web sites, we offer many features, like games and coloring books, which do not require a child to provide any personal information. We collect only limited personal information from children 12 and under (like their email addresses) to respond to their online requests. For example, we may collect a child's email address in order to send the child a screen saver, but we promptly delete the email address from our system. Or, we may collect a child's email address in order to enter the child in a sweepstakes. We may also ask a child to provide an email address of a parent so we can notify the parent or seek consent. We will not collect more detailed information from a child 12 and younger, such as a postal address or a telephone number, without the consent of a parent or guardian. McDonald's will not condition a child's participation in any online activity on the child's disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in that activity.

Personal information collected from children is used solely by McDonald's or other entities that provide technical, fulfillment or other services to McDonald's. For example, such entities may provide services, such as, improving our web sites, fulfilling requests or administering sweepstakes. This personal information is not sold or transferred to third parties.

We urge parents to regularly monitor and supervise their children's on-line activities.

## Access

You are in control of any personal information you provide to us on-line. If at any time, you would like to correct the personal information we have about you or if you would like to change your preferences for contacts from us or on behalf of our business partners, you can let us know by contacting us at the email or postal address listed below.

In order to review any personal information we have about you or to ask us to delete that information or to stop further use of the information, please submit this information request form.

In order to review any personal information we have about your child or to ask us to delete that information or to stop further use of the information, please submit this information request form.

## Cookies

"Cookies" are pieces of information that a web site transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies allow the web site to remember important information that will make your use of the site more convenient. Like most web sites, McDonald's uses cookies for a variety of purposes in order to improve your on-line experience. For example, we track the total number of visitors to our site on an anonymous aggregate basis. We may also employ cookies so that we remember you when you return to the site, to keep track of the items in your shopping cart if you purchase merchandise online, to administer certain contests and sweepstakes and to help customize your McDonald's web experience. We may associate personal information with a cookie file in those instances.

Use the options in your web browser if you do not wish to receive a cookie or if you wish to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. Click on the "Help" section of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you disable all cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all the features of this web site.

## Links to Other Sites

We may offer links to sites that are not operated by McDonald's Corporation. If you visit one of these linked sites, you should review their privacy and other policies. We are not responsible for the policies and practices of other companies, and any information you submit to those companies is subject to their privacy policies

## Other McDonald’s Websites

All McDonald's web sites operated by McDonald's Corporation will adhere to this privacy policy. The policies of some McDonald's sites may vary, however, because of local customs, practices or laws or due to circumstances unique to that site. In all cases, however, sites operated by McDonald's Corporation will honor the commitments to our customers set forth in this policy regarding the collection and use of personal information.

## McDonald’s Franchisee Websites

Many McDonald's restaurants are owned and operated by franchisees, who are independent businessmen and women. Some franchisees also operate web sites. In many cases, franchisee sites follow this privacy policy. However, please review the privacy policy of each site to determine the privacy policies of that site.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is effective as of June 8, 2004. From time to time, it may be necessary for McDonald's to change this privacy policy. If we change our policy, we will post the revised version here, so we suggest that you check here periodically for the most up-to-date version of our privacy policy. Rest assured, however, that any changes will not be retroactively applied and will not alter how we handle previously collected information.

## How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about our McDonald's Internet Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Privacy at McDonald's  
Dept. 062  
One Kroc Drive  
Oak Brook, IL 60523  
USA  
(800) 261-9827  
or e-mail us at [contact.privacy@us.mcd.com](mailto:contact.privacy@us.mcd.com)
